nicholas singh marketer. designer. innovator.

1066 Stewart Ave, Coquitlam 778.838.3926 nss8@sfu.ca



Summary

Passionate about branding and marketing communications within an organization. An outgoing, energetic, senior undergraduate majoring in Interactive Arts & Technology (SIAT) and Business Administration. Passionate about marketing and design, always looking for innovative solutions. Technically savvy and keen on designing for people with a focus on client needs. Has experience working in customer and client driven environments and regularly volunteers for various networking and social events. Applies teamwork, communication, collaboration, and leadership skills in all design-related projects.

Knowledge

Tech Specs

FINAL CUT PRO X MICROSOFT OFFICE

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR

Evaluate the technical knowledge and needs of customers,

educating them on Apple hardware and software. Enrichs

Independently accesses and assist with individual customer

of 60% Applecare and 40% One to One with 400% personal

customer experience by enabling and encouraging them to interact with hardware and software through guidance.

needs, building the best solution for them. Contribute \$100,000 in revenue per quarter. Work towards sales targets

AFTER EFFECTS DREAMWEAVER

ADOBE INDESIGN HTML/CSS/XML Design Knowledge

Wireframes Heirarchy Balance

SFU Bookstore

Colour Theory

Video Editing Green/Blue Screen Flow Interaction

User Testing

Eye movement

Work Experience

Apple

Specialist

2011-Present

Customer Service Associate

2009-2011

Efficiently counted and always had a balanced float. Multitasked between receiving, shelving books, while providing customer service, which ensured a great shopping experience.

The Real Canadian Superstore

2006-2008

Accurate money handling and bagging customers goods. Performed front end duties and price checking.

Futureshop

Sales Associate and Cashier

growth over two years.

2008-2009

Used product knowledge and interpersonal communication skills to create a rapport with customers to sell mobile audio products.

Education

Simon Fraser University

BBA Candidate, Business Administration and Interactive Arts & Technology

2008-Present

Expertise in the school's design concentration as well as broad business knowledge. Human-centred and technology oriented. Combining these aspects with business knowledge prepares for industry leadership positions, and provides a strong understanding of how to deploy design processes in larger managerial and technological contexts. In addition, will identify market and funding opportunities.

Achievements: Beedie School of Business Dean's Honour Roll Spring 2013, Beedie FROSH Chair

Portfolio: www.sfu.ca/~nss8/portfolio/store.html



Projects

The Raven: 11 Min Short Film

Group Project

Link: vimeo.com/54349584

Synopsis

Modern reimagining of the Edgar Allen Poe poem.

Role

Director, Camera Operator, Editor, Sound Designer, Cinematography, Screenplay, Co-Casting Director, Credits

Skills

Film editing, sound editing, screenplay, color editing, filming, sound recording, team direction, worked with professional actors

"Candy Box" Website Mockups

Individual Project

Link: www.sfu.ca/~nss8/portfolio/candybox.html

Design an online presence for a local candy store, learning the process to design a website. Involved creating over 40 sketches and wireframes for desktop and mobile websites.

Role

Graphic Designer, Usability Tester

Skills

Wireframes, sketches, illustrator, indesign

SFU Community

Beedie FROSH Senior Advisor

Interviewed, hired and trained the incoming Beedie FROSH Chair. Overlooked budget, training materials. Maintained and carried over culture and brand management from previous year. Maintained and iterated vision of event. Helped train 48 mentors and design training materials. Public speaking in front of 200+ students and speakers throughout the event.

SFU Business FROSH Volunteer Ligison

Responsible in recruiting and training 36 volunteers as well as creating tasks and itineraries for each day of the event. Heavily involved with the planning process of the event. Helped with design work for the event.

2011-2012 Beedie FROSH Chair

 Interviewed, hired, trained and worked with Organizing Committee to evolve and expand event over 6 months

2010-2011

- Interviewed over 120+ SFU Beedie Students, selecting and training 48 for mentors
- Developed a strong marketing and branding plan that allowed us to sell tickets to 184 incoming Beedie students and had a wait list of over 30 addition students
- Worked with my Organizing Committee to develop a new culture and brand for the event that has been received well and carried onward with the next year
- Public speaking in front of 200+ students and speakers throughout the event
- Expanded the budget \$8000 from previous year and worked with a budget of \$30,000, and received \$10500 through sponsorship

What I do for Fun

Enjoy watching and playing hockey, regularly following the Vancouver Canucks and reading about league activities. Exercising regularly, whether hiking on a trial, going for a run or P90X. Traveling, wanting to backpack throughout Europe, specifically Germany, Spain, France and return to Italy. Follow the latest trends in technology, especially in computers and video games. Enjoy socializing over food, trying a wide variety from dim sum to greek. Watch movies with a keen interest on all types, including indies and blockbusters.

2010